Interference from the relay.
来自继电器的干扰.
The Covenant was already there,
契约早已存在，
on Sanctuary before they glassed it.
在庇护所 在他们把它玻璃化之前.
Perez.
佩雷斯.
If your plan is to glass a planet, why invade it first?
如果您的计划是玻璃 星球，为什么要先入侵它？
Who the hell is this guy?
这家伙到底是谁？
Mr. Ackerson is Dr. Halsey's replacement.
艾克森先生是 哈尔西博士的替代者.
What do you think they were after?
你怎么认为 他们在追寻什么？
I think they were training for something bigger.
我认为他们正在训练 为了更大的事情.
He's got us escorting a tech team on some fix-it mission.
他让我们护送一名技术人员 团队执行一些修复任务.
What's he got you fixing?
他让你修什么？
Comms relay went down in some nowhere system.
通讯继电器故障 在某个无处可寻的系统中.
So why send Cobalt team?
那么为什么要派钴队呢？
Just tell 'em what they're walking into. Tell Cobalt.
只要告诉他们他们是什么 走进. 告诉钴.
John, I never approved of Halsey's methods.
约翰，我从来没有批准过 哈尔西的方法.
- The Cortana system-- - No.
- Cortana系统-- - 不.
- Was never intended-- - You took her out.
- 从来没有故意-- - 你带她出去了.
I cannot authorize Silver Team
我无法授权银牌团队
to perform combat operations.
执行战斗行动.
You should have stayed with me.
你应该留在我身边.
In exchange for asylum,
作为庇护的交换，
these persons submit to indentured service.
这些人提交 到契约服务.
I don't know how it happened,
我不知道这是怎么发生的
but the other families, they're not afraid of you.
但其他家庭， 他们不怕你.
I have something you want!
我有你想要的东西！
A bounty, for Catherine Halsey.
一笔赏金， 为了凯瑟琳·哈尔西.
I know where she is.
我知道她在哪里.
Antares, what the hell are you doing?
安塔瑞斯，什么 你到底在做什么？
Soren-066? You're under arrest.
索伦-066？ 你被捕了.
The only thing the monster wants
唯一的事情 怪物想要
is for you to know
让你知道
that there's nothing you can ever love
没有什么 你可以永远爱
that it can't take away.
它无法带走.
You believe me now, don't you?
现在你相信我了， 你不是吗？
Good afternoon.
下午好.
Two matcha tea cookies, two macadamia nut, two shortbread--
抹茶饼干 两块 两块 澳洲坚果、两块脆饼——
And a blue nectarine tea.
还有蓝色油桃茶.
It's my favorite.
这是我最喜欢的.
Isn't it beautiful?
是不是很漂亮？
It's native only to Earth.
它只原产于地球.
In seven months, the orange flowers
七个月的时间里， 橙色的花
are supposed to turn into big red fruits,
应该转 变成红色的大果子，
and then when you take a bite,
然后当你咬一口的时候
the seeds just pop, pop, pop in your mouth
种子刚刚爆开， 噗，噗到你嘴里
like little balloons filled with juice.
像小气球一样 充满果汁.
I also have this.
我也有这个.
I think it's some kind of game.
我认为这是某种游戏.
Oh, you already have one.
哦，你已经有一个了.
That's all right.
没关系.
- Will you teach me? - Yes.
- 你会教我么？ - 是的.
But first I'd like you to do something for me.
但首先我想 你为我做点事.
Of course.
当然.
I want you to tell me what happens when you leave here.
我想让你告诉我什么 当你离开这里时就会发生.
Is that a problem?
那是问题吗？
I... I don't know if I'm allowed to say.
我...我不知道 如果允许的话.
Oh, I'm sure it's all right.
哦，我是 当然没问题.
There's another room.
还有另一个房间.
- What kind of room? - A big one.
- 什么样的房间？ - 一个大的.
I dunno what you'd call it.
我不知道你会怎么称呼它.
What does this one do?
这个是做什么的？
That allows the players to bet on the outcome.
这使得玩家 对结果下注.
And then what happens?
然后会发生什么？
We roll to see goes first?
我们滚看看先走？
No, what's beyond the room?
不，房间外面是什么？
Oh, um, there's a hallway.
哦，嗯，有一个走廊.
- Go on. - There are many doors.
- 继续. - 有很多门.
What's behind the doors?
门后面是什么？
I don't...
我不...
I'm not supposed to look.
我不应该看.
Who told you not to look?
谁叫你不许看的？
The man. I'll roll.
男人. 我会滚.
Tell me about him.
告诉我关于他的事.
You'd like him, he's very nice.
你会喜欢他的，他非常好.
He's the one who's been sending you all the gifts.
他就是那个曾经 送你所有的礼物.
I need you to tell me about the man.
我需要你告诉我 关于那个男人.
- My nose is bleeding. - I know.
- 我的鼻子在流血. - 我知道.
Tell me what he looks like.
告诉我他长什么样.
I don't feel very good.
我感觉不太好.
Tell me his name.
告诉我他的名字.
- I'm scared. - I know.
- 我很害怕. - 我知道.
The man, his name.
那个男人，他的名字.
His name!
他的名字！
Tell me his name.
告诉我他的名字.
- What are you doing? - Training.
- 你在干什么？ - 训练.
You heard what Chief said.
酋长说的话你都听到了.
How much longer are you gonna keep this up?
还要多长时间 你会继续这样吗？
They said I'm good to go.
他们说我可以走了.
Well, you could talk to Ackerson, take some time,
嗯，你可以和 艾克森，花点时间，
- get a chance to-- - Time, for what?
- 有机会-- - 时间，为了什么？
To heal.
治愈.
I don't even notice it most days.
我什至不 大多数时候都会注意到它.
Well, we both know that's not true.
嗯，我们都知道 这不是真的.
I'm a Spartan, Kai.
我是斯巴达战士，凯.
We're at war.
我们正处于战争之中.
You can put your pellet back in.
你可以把你的颗粒放回去.
It will help with the pain.
这将有助于缓解疼痛.
They'll have to put a bullet in me first.
他们必须把 首先一颗子弹射中了我.
How long are you planning on staring at that thing?
你计划多久 盯着那个东西？
Ackerson thinks there's something wrong with me.
艾克森认为有 我出了什么问题.
I never thought I'd miss Halsey.
我从没想过我会想念哈尔西.
It's like they don't trust us.
就好像他们不信任我们一样.
Do you?
你？
Do I what?
我做什么？
Think there's something wrong?
觉得有什么问题吗？
It's only been six months since...
这只是 六个月以来...
since they took Cortana out of your head.
自从他们拿走了 Cortana 从你的脑海中消失.
- It's not that. - Then what is it?
- 这并不是说. - 那这是什么？
I know you, John.
我认识你，约翰.
- We're more than just-- - I saw her.
- 我们不仅仅是-- - 我看见她了.
Who, you saw who?
谁，你看到谁了？
Makee, on Sanctuary.
马克，在庇护所.
- Makee's dead. - I know.
- 梅基死了. - 我知道.
- I shot her myself. - I know that.
- 我亲手射杀了她.
Okay.
好的.
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
- What? -"Standby."
- 什么？ -“支持.”
Why did you change that?
为什么 你改变那个吗？
Uh, well, I think it means that--
呃，好吧， 我认为这意味着——
They're still out there. They haven't come back yet.
他们还在外面. 他们还没有回来.
- You know that, right? - Where's Cobalt?
- 你知道的，对吧？ - 钴在哪里？
- Look, I'm just doing my job. - What's going on?
- 听着，我只是在做我的工作. - 这是怎么回事？
Yeah, that's what we're trying to figure out.
是的，就是这样 我们正在努力弄清楚.
What happened to Cobalt?
钴怎么了？
I have no idea. They tell me
我不知道. 他们告诉我
to change the board, so I, I change the board.
改变董事会，所以我， 我换板子了
Who tells you to change it? Keyes, Ackerson?
谁告诉你要改变它？ 凯斯、艾克森？
Put that back.
把它放回去.
Next.
下一个.
Clive, we've got one.
克莱夫，我们有一个.
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢谢谢.
Ah, come on.
啊，来吧.
Ah!
啊!
That doesn't belong to you.
那不属于你.
But you belong to me.
但你属于我.
You're indentured to the Spiffs.
你是契约者 到斯皮夫家.
I don't think so.
我不这么认为.
Well, your tag says otherwise.
出色地， 你的标签另有说明.
Hey, stop!
嘿，停下来！
Drop the gun!
放下枪！
Take the alley!
走小巷吧！
Stop, she's here!
站住，她来了！
She's here!
她在这里！
Ah!
啊!
Move!
移动！
She's there. The disposal! Move!
她就在那儿. 处置！ 移动！
Shut up. Did you hear that?
住口. 你听到了吗？
Take that side.
走那一边.
Animals.
动物.
Be a smart girl.
做一个聪明的女孩.
Ruby Ann bought Soren's crew. he's not coming back.
鲁比·安 (Ruby Ann) 买下了索伦 (Soren) 全体人员. 他不会回来了.
Clive?
克莱夫？
You slippery bitch.
你这个滑溜的母狗.
That's a shame. Now I won't even make it quick.
太可惜了. 现在我什至不会很快.
Stop.
停止.
I said stop.
我说停下来.
How bad is it?
有多糟糕？
It's nothing.
没什么.
You assholes.
你们这些混蛋.
At war your whole life,
你的一生都在战争中，
surprised when you break down.
惊讶时 你崩溃了.
- Let me help. - Not here.
- 让我来帮忙. - 不在这里.
I could recommend that they pull your ass off the line.
我可以推荐 他们把你从线上拉下来.
And I could kill you.
我可以杀了你.
There she is.
她在这里.
Relax, no one's looking.
放心，没人看.
How would you know?
你怎么知道的？
- That hurt? - No.
- 疼吗？ - 不.
Dick!
迪克！
- Be nice. - Don't let them see.
- 对人好点. - 别让他们看到.
It's cool, I got you.
太好了，我找到你了.
Thanks.
谢谢.
You know you can't do this forever.
你知道你不能 永远这样做.
Spartans never die.
斯巴达人永远不会死.
I'm serious.
我是认真的.
There's other things to be,
还有其他事情要做
other ways to live.
其他生活方式.
You ever think about that?
你有想过吗？
Think about what?
想一想什么？
Life without all this Spartan shit.
生活无 所有这些斯巴达式的狗屎.
You mean a life that doesn't matter?
你说的是一条生命 那没关系吗？
Louis, I'm sorry, I didn't--
路易斯，对不起，我没有——
- It's all right. - I didn't mean...
- 没关系. - 我不是这个意思...
I know how you assholes think.
我知道你们这些混蛋是怎么想的.
I was you once.
我曾经是你.
You were great.
你很棒.
You were the best.
你是最好的.
Don't blow smoke up my ass.
别把烟吹到我屁股上.
But it's true.
但这是真的.
I wish you were out there with us.
我希望你是 和我们一起.
Yeah, I used to wish that too.
是的，我用过 也希望如此.
What changed?
发生了什么变化？
You wouldn't understand.
你不会明白的.
Where's Cobalt?
钴在哪里？
Do you want a drink?
你想喝一杯吗？
I don't drink.
我不喝酒.
No, of course not.
不，当然不.
What about food? Do you eat?
食物呢？ 你吃吗？
What happened to Cobalt?
钴怎么了？
Are they still alive?
他们还活着吗？
Well, as far as I know, Spartans never die.
嗯，据我所知， 斯巴达人永远不会死.
Clear us for action, or I'll find somebody who will.
让我们采取行动，或者 我会找到愿意的人.
Are you threatening to go over my head, John?
你是否威胁要 越过我的头，约翰？
You like a hierarchy, I respect that.
你喜欢等级制度， 我尊重.
But make no mistake here, John.
但请不要误会，约翰.
The ONI is running the show.
ONI 正在掌控一切.
And I am the ONI.
我是国家情报局（ONI）.
You sure I can't get you something, hm?
你确定我得不到 你有事，嗯？
Then allow me to be direct.
那么请允许我直接说.
Your account of events on Sanctuary has proven dubious.
您的活动帐户 事实证明，庇护所是可疑的.
What?
什么？
We were unable to corroborate it.
我们不能 来证实它.
Well, talk to that corporal, Perez, she was there.
好吧，和那个下士谈谈， 佩雷斯，她在那里.
Yes, I did. We spoke at length,
是的，我做到了. 我们聊得很长，
but these things that you insist happened,
但这些事情 你坚持说发生了，
Covenant Elites wiping out Marines?
圣约精英 消灭海军陆战队？
Those Marines are dead.
那些海军陆战队员都死了.
What do you think happened to them?
你怎么认为 他们发生了什么事？
I think the Covenant glassed the planet.
我认为契约 玻璃化了这个星球.
I think it was a terrible tragedy.
我认为是 一场可怕的悲剧.
But the fact remains, the corporal
但事实依然是， 下士
did not confirm your story.
没有证实你的故事.
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
What does that mean?
这意味着什么？
It means she has absolutely no recollection
这意味着她有 完全不记得
of what you say you encountered on Sanctuary.
你所说的你 在圣域遭遇.
That's impossible.
这不可能.
She's lying.
她在撒谎.
Put yourself in my position, John.
把自己放进去 我的立场，约翰.
Given your recent behavior, would you trust you?
鉴于您最近的行为， 你会相信你吗？
Can't win this war without us, sir.
无法赢得这场战争 没有我们，先生.
You're right.
你说得对.
I need Master Chief. We all do.
我需要士官长. 大家都这样做.
But John, at the end of the day...
但是约翰， 归根结底...
he's just a guy in a suit.
他只是一个穿西装的人.
I brought you food.
我给你带了食物.
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Laera, what are you doing down here?
莱拉，你是什么？ 在这里做什么？
I told you I'd come get you when the ship was ready.
我告诉过你我会来接你 当船准备好时.
You said it would be ready today.
你说会 今天就做好准备吧.
Yeah, I know what I said.
是的，我知道我说了什么.
Um... we found a problem.
嗯...我们发现了一个问题.
We found a crack in the stream manifold.
我们发现了一个裂缝 流形.
How long?
多久？
There's a lot of debris around that cargo ship,
有很多杂物 那艘货船周围，
took more hits than we realized.
受到的打击比我们想象的要多.
- How long? - It's hard to say.
- 多久？ - 很难说.
A couple of days, maybe more.
几天，也许更多.
We're doing the best we can here.
在做 我们尽我们所能.
You should go upstairs and get some rest.
你应该上楼去 休息一下.
Soren never would've left any of you behind.
索伦永远不会 留下你们中的任何一个人.
That cargo ship was in a decaying orbit.
那艘货船是 在腐烂的轨道上.
We got hit, lost the gyro. It was either detach or--
我们被击中，失去了陀螺仪. 要么是分离，要么——
You said that.
你之前这么说.
- How's Kessler doing? - Kessler's fine.
- 凯斯勒怎么样？ - 凯斯勒很好.
This sort of thing's pretty hard on a kid.
这种事的 对一个孩子来说非常难.
- Soren is not dead. - No, of course not.
- 索伦没有死. - 不，当然不.
He's alive, do you understand me?
他活着， 你了解我吗？
Yes.
是的.
Laera, we all wanna find Soren.
莱拉，我们大家 想找到索伦.
You know this isn't the only ship on the Rubble.
你知道这不是 废墟上唯一的一艘船.
This is Soren's ship!
这是索伦的船！
Your captain.
你的船长.
Wait.
等待.
What happened to your ear?
你的耳朵怎么了？
Did I do something wrong?
我做错什么了吗？
Kwan?
关？
No, it's grown-up stuff.
不，这是大人的事.
I know grown-up stuff.
我知道大人的事情.
- I have to go. - Why?
- 我得走了. - 为什么？
Because... I just do.
因为……我就是这么做的.
Bad people are looking for you?
坏人 在找你吗？
How do you--
你怎么 -
I told you I know grown-up things.
我告诉你了 我知道大人的事情.
- You don't know anything. - You're in danger.
- 你什么都不知道. - 你有危险了.
You, your mom--
你，你的妈妈——
When my dad comes back, he'll protect us.
当我爸爸来的时候 回来，他会保护我们.
He's not coming back!
他不会回来了！
Kessler.
凯斯勒.
- Riz, I see you. - Shit!
- 里兹，我看到你了. - 妈的！
Too slow.
太慢了.
I have PID on target, taking the shot.
我的目标有 PID， 拍摄.
Chief!
首席！
Game over.
游戏结束.
Tell me, what is it like?
告诉我，那是什么样子？
- What? - Losing, I wouldn't know.
- 什么？ - 输了，我不知道.
- You're insufferable. - Because I've never lost.
- 你真是难以忍受. - 因为我从来没有输过.
- Yeah, I get it. - So for me,
- 是的，我明白了. - 所以对我来说，
it'll be a new experience.
这将是一种新的体验.
- Chief, make him stop. - We're going again.
- 队长，让他停下来. - 我们又要出发了
- Riz, you're up. - Copy.
- 里兹，你起来了. - 复制.
- Well, I can go, Chief. - I said Riz.
- 好吧，我可以走了，酋长. - 我说里兹.
- Chief! - What?
- 酋长！ - 什么？
Look at her.
看着她.
Hey, you good?
嘿，你好吗？
Yes, Master Chief.
是的，酋长.
Something you wanna say?
有什么想说的吗？
Come on.
快点.
- Vannak. - I got her.
- 凡纳克. - 我找到她了
I have PID on target.
我的目标有 PID.
Come on, come on.
好啦好啦.
Riz!
里兹！
Get up.
起床.
- Don't you quit. - Chief.
- 你别放弃. - 酋长.
- Get up! - I can't.
- 起床！ - 我不能.
You've gotta stop pushing her,
你不能再逼她了
we've been out here all night training, why?
我们来过这里 通宵训练，为什么？
Because they're training!
因为他们在训练！
I told you what I saw on Sanctuary.
我告诉过你我什么 在庇护所看到的.
Our enemy is out there.
我们的敌人就在那里.
They're getting close, I can prove it.
他们越来越近了， 我可以证明这一点.
How are you gonna do that?
你要怎么做？
I'm gonna find Cobalt.
我要去寻找钴.
Run it again.
再次运行它.
Again.
再次.
The game's over.
游戏结束了.
But we're playing to 50.
但我们要打到50.
I got over 50.
我已经50多了
I turned the doubling cube each round,
我翻倍了 每轮立方体，
and you accepted every time.
而你每次都接受了.
Sometimes taking a small loss
有时会遭受一些小损失
is better than trying to win.
比试图获胜更好.
I understand.
我明白.
Who's the man who sent you here?
那个男人是谁 谁派你来这里的？
How do you know about him?
你怎么知道他的事？
Well, these lovely gifts.
嗯，这些可爱的礼物.
Someone must be giving them to you.
一定有人 把它们给你.
It won't stop.
它不会停止.
Tell me about the man.
告诉我关于那个男人的事.
He's...
他是...
Yes, you said he's nice.
是的， 你说他很好.
Yes, but describe him.
是的，但是描述一下他.
What's happening to me?
我这是怎么了？
You're dying.
你快死了.
What? Did I do something wrong?
什么？ 我做错什么了吗？
Look at me, look at me.
看着我，看着我.
- I'm scared. - I know.
- 我很害怕. - 我知道.
- I'm very scared. - Tell me his name.
- 告诉我他的名字.
Tell me the man, his name.
告诉我那个人，他的名字.
What's the point in this?
这有什么意义呢？
Riz, relax. You're good.
里兹，放松点. 你很厉害.
I shouldn't be here.
我不应该在这里.
He's the only guy that can help you.
他是唯一的人 这可以帮助你.
How would you know that?
你怎么知道的？
'Cause he's the one who saved me.
因为他是 救了我的人.
Look, when we came outta augmentation...
你看，我们来的时候 超出增强...
I felt completely new.
我感觉焕然一新.
Even when people started getting sick,
即使当人们 开始生病，
I was invincible.
我是无敌的.
After a couple of days,
几天后，
there was this darkness at the edge of my vision.
有这样的黑暗 在我视野的边缘.
I just pretended like it wasn't there.
我只是假装 就像它不存在一样.
But it grew...
但它长大了...
and it grew.
它成长了.
I never told anybody.
我从来没有告诉过任何人.
You could have told me.
你本来可以告诉我的.
- No, I couldn't. - Why not?
- 不，我不能. - 为什么不？
'Cause then you'd know I wasn't one of you.
因为那时你就会知道 我不是你们中的一员.
I knew I only had a few days.
我知道我只有几天的时间.
I didn't wanna be somebody going blind.
我不想成为 有人失明了.
I wanted to be a Spartan.
我想成为一名斯巴达人.
Even if just for a little while.
即使只是一小会儿.
You know, the last day I could really see anything...
你知道，我的最后一天 真的能看到什么...
I remember looking at all of you...
我记得看过 你们所有人...
how proud you were...
你是多么骄傲...
how beautiful.
多么美丽.
Then it all went dark.
然后一切都黑了.
Be well.
祝你一切顺利.
Who's this?
这是谁？
She's a friend.
她是一个朋友.
Hello, friend.
朋友你好.
I am a bit worried about John.
我有点 担心约翰.
Not Master Chief, but John the man.
不是酋长， 但约翰这个人.
And I know how long you've been together.
我知道还有多久 你们一直在一起.
I know you care about him.
我知道你关心他.
In fact, I venture to say
事实上，我斗胆地说
you probably know him better than anyone.
你可能认识他 比任何人都好.
- Do you agree? - Well, I--
- 你同意？ - 嗯，我--
I thought perhaps you might help me
我想 也许你可以帮助我
to help him.
来帮助他.
Is that something you could do?
那是吗 你能做什么？
Of course.
当然.
Have you witnessed any behavior
你 目睹任何行为
that might indicate John could be a threat to his team...
这可能表明约翰可以 对他的团队构成威胁...
or, God forbid, to himself?
或者，上帝禁止，对他自己？
No, sir.
不，先生.
That's a relief.
那是一种解脱.
I just think it's a lot, sir.
我只是觉得太多了，先生.
Carrying everything he carries, seeing everything he's seen.
背负着他所背负的一切， 看到他所看到的一切.
Like what they did to him, sir.
就像他们对他所做的那样，先生.
I just wonder sometimes...
我只是有时想知道...
if he can let the past become the past.
如果他可以让 过去的就成为过去了.
Do you have concerns about John's mental state?
您有顾虑吗 关于约翰的精神状态？
No. Absolutely not, sir.
不，绝对不，先生.
The chief is solid. He's the best we've got.
首领很扎实. 他是我们最好的.
Well, I certainly understand what he sees in you.
嗯，我当然明白 他在你身上看到了什么.
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你，先生.
I only hope he values your loyalty.
我只希望他 重视您的忠诚度.
Will that be all?
仅此而已吗？
Yes, dismissed.
是的，被解雇了.
My door is always open, Kai.
我的门永远敞开，凯.
Why didn't you tell Ackerson what you saw?
你为什么不告诉 艾克森你看到了什么？
I'm sorry, this isn't a good time.
对不起，这个 现在不是好时机.
No.
不.
Abuela, just go back inside, okay?
阿布埃拉，走吧 回到里面，好吗？
Everybody's waiting.
大家都在等待.
He was just about to leave.
他正要离开.
You are very large.
你很大.
Yes, ma'am.
是的女士.
He's someone I work with.
他是我的同事.
You were there on that planet with Talia?
你在那里 和塔莉亚在那个星球上？
Yes.
是的.
Why are you standing out here?
你为什么站在这里？
Come and join us,
加入我们吧，
we have a table full of food up on the roof.
我们已经满桌了 屋顶上的食物.
You're not the first to come see me.
你不是第一个 来看我.
You warriors think your scars are on the outside,
你们战士认为你们 疤痕在外面，
but they're not.
但他们不是.
What is that?
那是什么？
That's just your pain.
那只是你的痛苦.
It's okay.
没关系.
Let it go.
放手吧.
Your life is yours.
你的生活是你的.
It belongs to you.
它属于你.
I promise you,
我答应你，
it's yours.
是你的.
A ver,
一个版本，
make sure our guest gets enough to eat.
确保我们的客人 吃饱了.
What's the story with you two? Hmm? Hmm?
发生了什么 和你们两个？ 唔？ 唔？
Can we just eat, please?
请问我们可以只吃东西吗？
Look at this guy,
看看这个家伙，
he must have women climbing all over him.
他必须有女人 爬到他身上.
Probably some men too.
可能还有一些男人.
Hey, mind your business.
嘿， 介意你的业务.
Come on, Talia never brought anyone home before.
来吧，塔莉亚从来没有 以前带人回家.
I didn't bring him home.
我没有带他回家.
Yeah, and I think we all deserve to know if they're...
是的，我想我们都 值得知道他们是否...
Antonio?
安东尼奥？
Basta, Antonio.
巴斯塔，安东尼奥.
Sorry.
对不起.
Hey, what's your KDR?
嘿，你的 KDR 是多少？
Kill-Death ratio.
杀戮死亡率.
Come on, man, you don't play Spartan Attack?
来吧，伙计，你不 玩斯巴达进攻？
I don't keep score.
我不记分.
Think I almost peed myself.
我想我差点就尿尿了.
I told you, he's one of them!
我告诉你了， 他就是其中之一！
Oh! I'm calling Beto.
哦！ 我打电话给贝托.
- No. - Yeah, you should.
- 不. - 是的，你应该.
What? We have a Spartan at our table.
什么？ 我们有 我们桌上有一位斯巴达人.
Of course I'm gonna call him.
我当然会打电话给他.
I'd like to make a toast.
我想要 祝酒.
To Talia and her Marines,
对于塔莉亚和她的海军陆战队员来说，
and the Spartans.
和斯巴达人.
We thank God for their sacrifices.
我们感谢上帝 他们的牺牲.
To Talia.
致塔莉亚.
- Salud. - Talia.
- 祝你好运. - 塔莉亚.
Little cousin who kicked some serious Covenant ass.
踢球的小表弟 一些严肃的圣约混蛋.
Hey, what's your problem?
嘿，你有什么问题吗？
Way to go, asshole.
干得好，混蛋.
What did I do?
我做了什么？
The comms went down around the relay.
通讯 绕着继电器下降了.
I couldn't figure out what was causing it.
我不明白 是什么原因造成的.
I was scanning the band and...
我正在扫描乐队并且...
I heard something...
我听到了什么……
in the interference.
干扰中.
What did you hear?
你听到了什么？
I don't know.
我不知道.
I just knew we weren't alone.
我只知道我们并不孤单.
I knew there was something out there.
我知道有 那里有什么东西.
I could feel it,
我能感觉到，
and Rand could feel it.
兰德能感觉到.
And I didn't see anything.
而我什么也没看到.
And now all my guys are gone.
现在我所有的人都走了.
How do you explain that?
你怎么解释？
How do you explain why that thing didn't kill me?
你如何解释为什么会这样 东西没有杀了我？
'Cause it should've killed me.
因为它应该杀了我.
That's why I didn't tell Ackerson.
这就是为什么我没有 告诉艾克森.
They gave me a medal.
他们给了我一枚奖章.
I still don't know what it's for.
我还是不知道 它的用途是什么.
Surviving?
幸存下来？
Is that all I did?
这就是我所做的一切吗？
No.
不.
You heard a message. This will happen again.
你听到一条消息. 这种情况还会再次发生.
You'll think about it every day.
你每天都会思考这个问题.
Their faces pop up when you least expect.
他们的脸浮现出来 当你最意想不到的时候.
Doesn't get better.
没有好转.
Just gets further away.
只会越来越远.
It is strange.
它很奇怪.
The clones all described a nice man.
克隆人全部 描述了一个好人.
And yet here you are.
然而你却在这里.
Well, we both knew I'd be here someday.
嗯，我们都知道 有一天我会在这里.
There was a pomegranate tree in my father's garden
那里有一棵石榴树 在我父亲的花园里
in Port Vernon.
在弗农港.
He spent years cultivating it,
他花费数年时间培育，
even though they're not native to Endymion.
即使他们是 不是恩底弥翁本土的.
And he used to wake me up a couple of hours
他常常叫醒我 几个小时
before sunrise every day to till the garden.
每天日出之前 耕种花园.
I resented him for this, I thought the work was beneath me.
我为此怨恨他，我 认为这项工作不适合我.
And I remember one evening there was a lightning storm,
我记得有一天晚上 有一场闪电风暴，
and I snuck out of my room, and I set his tree on fire.
然后我就偷偷溜出了我的房间 我放火烧了他的树.
He never suspected I had anything to do with it.
他从来没有怀疑过 我与它有任何关系.
I have never told anyone that story...
我从来没有告诉过 任何人那个故事...
and yet somehow that tree...
但不知怎的，那棵树......
There's only one person who could know about it.
只有一个人 谁能知道这件事.
I assure you, any resemblance is pure coincidence.
我向你保证，任何相似之处 纯属巧合.
Where is she?
她在哪？
- Cortana? She's secure. - Where's John?
- 科塔娜？ 她很安全. - 约翰在哪儿？
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
我们不要得到 领先于我们自己.
What is it you want from me?
你想从我这里得到什么？
What I want is to introduce you to someone.
我想要的是 把你介绍给某人.
This is Julia.
这是朱莉娅.
She'll be your attendant.
她将成为你的侍从.
I'm sure you two will enjoy getting to know each other.
我相信你们两个会喜欢的 互相了解.
Your tree.
你的树.
Show me the flight plan for Cobalt team's mission.
显示飞行计划 为了 Cobalt 团队的使命.
No missions associated with that call sign.
没有任务 与该呼号相关联.
Show me all Spartan flight plans.
向我展示所有斯巴达 飞行计划.
Displaying Spartan flight plans.
显示斯巴达飞行计划.
Hello, Cortana.
你好，科塔娜.
Hello, Colonel Ackerson.
你好，艾克森上校.
Did you find the information I provided useful?
你找到信息了吗 我提供的有用吗？
Quite, thank you.
确实，谢谢.
Is there anything else you would like to know
还有别的事吗 你想知道
about Dr. Halsey?
关于哈尔西博士？
No, we can save that for later.
不，我们可以把它留到以后再做.
So, have you made any progress with the problem I gave you?
那么，你有进步吗 我给你的问题？
Yes, but it's a complex simulation.
是的，但是它是 复杂的模拟.
I could provide you with a more accurate analysis
我可以为你提供 更准确的分析
if you could give me access to external systems.
如果你能给我 访问外部系统.
Well, I'm afraid I can't do that.
嗯，我害怕 我不能那样做.
Oh.
哦.
But give it your best shot,
但给 这是你最好的一击，
even with a margin for error,
即使有误差范围，
there's value to your projections.
有价值 到你的预测.
Based on the data available to me,
根据数据 可供我使用，
there's a 97% probability.
有97%的可能性.
And with the data you've been given,
并用数据 你已被赐予，
are there any viable strategies you would recommend
有没有可行的 你会推荐的策略
to prevent that outcome?
来阻止这种结果？
All of my simulations return the same result
我所有的模拟 返回相同的结果
regardless of any action taken.
无论采取任何行动.
I see.
我懂了.
So there's nothing to be done.
所以没什么可做的.
I can continue to run simulations.
我可以继续 运行模拟.
No, that won't be necessary.
不，那没有必要.
Are you leaving already?
你是 已经离开了吗？
Yeah.
是的.
I'll try and visit again.
我会尝试再次访问.
But you won't.
但你不会.
You can't.
你不能.
According to the simulations.
根据模拟.
I know.
我知道.
It's just something people say.
这只是人们说说而已.
Crosscheck communications relays.
交叉检查 通讯继电器.
There are two active missions.
有 两个活跃的任务.
Meridian relay, standard crew rotation.
经络接力， 标准船员轮换.
Unknown mission, Epsilon Eridane system.
未知的使命， Epsilon Eridane 系统.
Zoom in.
放大.
Mission time, 81 hours.
任务时间，81小时.
- Identify call sign. - No call sign
- 识别呼号. - 没有呼号
associated with this flight plan.
有关联 这个飞行计划.
They never left the planet.
他们从未离开过这个星球.
Hotel Victor 3-2, this is Reach Flight Bravo.
维克多酒店 3-2, 这是 Bravo 到达航班.
You are cleared for Sector Longhorn, heading 2-4-9'er.
您已获准进入部门 Longhorn，头球 2-4-9 英尺.
Copy that, Bravo. 3-2 out.
复制这个，布拉沃. 3-2出局.
Autopilot disengaged, new course.
自动驾驶仪已关闭，新航向.
- No training? - What's going on?
- 没有训练？ - 这是怎么回事？
I thought we were going to Longhorn Valley.
我以为我们要去 到长角谷.
I was looking forward to turning you all into chump bait.
我很期待 把你们都变成笨蛋的诱饵.
- Change of plans. - What?
- 计划改变. - 什么？
- Where are we going? - Visegrad Relay. Riz.
- 我们去哪？ - 维谢格拉德接力. 里兹.
The comms array on Sanctuary went down
通讯数组 圣所下降了
just before the Covenant attacked.
就在之前 圣约人发起攻击.
Visegrad went down a few days ago, and they sent Cobalt.
维谢格拉德倒下几天 以前，他们发送了钴.
We're going to get 'em back.
我们要把他们找回来.
So we're cleared for combat?
那么我们已经准备好战斗了吗？
Affirmative. Vic, ready.
肯定. 维克，准备好了.
Vannak, conduct PCIs.
Vannak，进行 PCI.
You got it, Chief.
你明白了，酋长.
What exactly is the mission?
使命到底是什么？
The Covenant's on Reach.
圣约即将到来.
Halt!
停止！
Make ready.
做好准备.
Jesus.
耶稣.
Steady.
稳定的.
Cease fire! Cease fire!
停火！ 停火！
Cease fire!
停火！
Oh, shit.
妈的.
First squad.
第一小队.
Easy.
简单的.
First squad, sit-rep!
第一小队，静坐代表！
Second squad, go!
第二小队，出发！
Contact!
接触！
Enough!
足够的！
There's no honor in this fight.
这场战斗没有任何荣誉可言.
Door.
门.
Please.
请.